JOREN ABAT

DIGIAL MEDIA CONTENT CREATOR

647-710-6008 | abatjoren@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/joren-abat

SKILLS

Digital Media

- Content Creation
- Media Design
- Podcast Production
- Music Production
- Video Production
- Multimedia Art
- New Media Art
- Webpage Design

Tools & Software

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Premiere Pro
- Twitch
- YouTube Live
- Discord
- OBS
- Microsoft Office
- Google Drive

Programming

- C#
- C++
- Java
- Python
- Unity

Volunteer Activities

- Student Code Coach
- Community Volunteer at Ryerson University

Languages

- English
- French

HOBBIES

Video Games

- Enjoys playing a multitude of video games for the challenge and also for relaxation

Music

- Enjoys listening, creating and writing music of differing genres

Cooking

- Enjoys following recipes to create a meal and improve on my cooking ability

ABOUT ME

I'm a recent graduate with a Bachelor's Degree in New Media focusing on Game Design, Development and Computational Media with more than 5 years of practical experience in video editing and online media. As a digital media creator who can bridge the creative and technical aspects of digital content, I enjoy merging my digital skills with innovative processes to create impact.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF FINE ARTS IN NEW MEDIA (BFA)

Ryerson University, Faculty of Communication and Design, 2017 - 2021

- Concentration in Computational Media
- Focus in Game Design, Programming and Transmedia Storytelling
- Graduated with distinction

EXPERIENCE

TECHNICAL PRODUCER & EXHIBITOR, NEW MEDIA META 2021

Ryerson University | April 2021

This three day virtual event showcased thesis work of various New Media graduate students in a virtual gallery space. Interviews were conducted and livestreamed on the website to give insight to the artist's work

- Worked as one of the major live event producers, using OBS to broadcast interviews live
- Exhibited my Thesis project <u>Kiralyst Cover Concert: Virtual Immersion</u>
- Coordinated with other producers to ensure that minimal issues arose

CONTENT CREATOR & PARTNER & EDITOR

YouTube & Twitch | April 2011 - Present

Manages multiple YouTube channels of varying content: <u>KiralystMusic</u> & <u>Kira's Vtuber Clips</u> Additionally creates content and streams on Twitch: <u>Kiralyst</u>

- KiralystMusic focuses on music videos that I have created to support my hobby as a musical artist
- Kira's Vtuber Clips involves the editing of short form video of other content creator's livestreams into a digestible package
- Make use of software such as Premiere pro, After Effects, Photoshop, OBS, etc...

FREELANCE DIGITAL MEDIA CONSULTANT

- Created Short form edited videos for multiple online Content Creators | 2021
- Created, Co-Hosted and the Main Editor for 20 episodes of <u>Gamer Time; the way home podcast</u> | 2019 2020
- Created Birthday Celebration video for Twitch Streamer Nagzz21 which involved over 50 people | September 2021
- Created Music videos for INCinema, a film production arm of Iglesia Ni Cristo | 2021-2022

₹ PROJECTS

KIRALYST COVER CONCERT: VIRTUAL IMMERSION

https://jorenabat.com/KCC.html | 2020 - 2021

Kiralyst Cover Concert: Virtual Immersion is a virtual concert experience incorporating the use of an anime-inspired aesthetic.

- Planned, organized and created a VR virtual concert experience using Unity while incorporating the use of an anime-inspired aesthetic
- Heavily inspired by Hatsune Miku, I turned myself into a virtual singer using a multitude of programs such as Unity, Blender, UTAU, MMD, etc...

VARIOUS SMALL VIDEO GAMES

Novum - A Post Apocalyptic 3D Platformer | 2020

Novum is a 3D collectathon platformer built in Unity that features the playable character exploring an abandonned post-apocalyptic city after an epidemic takes over

- Worked alongside a partner in developing the game
- Focused on the coding aspect of the project

Johnny Smoke - A 2D Side scrolling Platformer | 2019

Out in the land of the tobacco plant, comes a tall, hard-ridin', lean bloke. He goes by the name of Johnny Smoke. Construct 2 based 2d sidescroller shooter platformer game

- Worked in a team of 4 to create the game
- Focused on implementing and coding the final product